

Francesco Zaniol

Senior Frontend Engineer • Contractor / Freelance • Remote EU <u>fzaniol@gmail.com</u>

About

I am a Senior Frontend Engineer with 15 years of industry experience.

I build fast, user-friendly, secure and accessible websites and apps, while delivering robust and efficient solutions. Throughout my career I have contributed to products and campaigns for renowned international brands.

I work remotely from Italy on a B2B contract basis, short or long term.

Quick links

- Personal page, a short presentation of my professional background.
- Linkedin profile, a more detailed overview of my skills and experiences.

Top skills

VueJS • Nuxt • Typescript • ES5+ • Vanilla • Accessibility • SPA • Design Systems • Testing • HTML5 • CSS3 • SASS/LESS • Tailwind • Animations • Agile • Responsive Design • Git • API • Webpack • Vite • UX • GraphQL • Debugging • Performance • SEO • Cross-browser • Web Components • PHP • Laravel • Wordpress • DRY • Teamplayer

Work experience

MAIZE | H-FARM Innovation | JAKALA

2018-2023 (5 years 6 months) • Italy (Full remote)

Role: Senior Frontend Engineer

VueJS, Nuxt, TypeScript, Testing, Design Systems, Laravel, Animations, Agile

Clients: Italian Industry Leaders and Multinational Corporations

Bulgari, Loro Piana, SNAM, Henkel, Barilla, Aquafil, other brands under NDA in the fields of: Banking, Insurance, Luxury, Eyewear, Automotive, Telecoms, Clothing, Digital Learning, Aerospace, Defense and Security

IE Agency

2014-2017 (3 years) • Melbourne, Australia

Role: Lead Frontend Developer • movember.com

Team Lead & Mentor, Agile, Design System, Testing, PHP, Zend

Client: The Movember Foundation

World's top 100 NGOs • Global Fundraising | 1.8 billion raised | 1.7 million participants

H-ART | AKQA

2012-2013 (1 year 6 months) • Italy

Role: Animation Frontend Developer

Animations, Landing Pages, Wordpress, Drupal

Clients: Italian Industry Leaders and Multinational Corporations

FIAT, Telecom Italia, GEOX, Barilla, IKEA, Illy, Bacardi, Fendi, Intesa Sanpaolo, OVS, Alessi, Poste Italiane, Toyota, Whirpool, other brands under NDA in the fields of: Food & Drink Industry, Automotive, Banking, Insurance, Luxury, Telecoms, Clothing, Home Appliances

accessibletemplate.com

2012-2017 (5 years 2 months) • Worldwide | Online digital store

Role: Founder • Fullstack Engineer

Accessibility, Personal Business, Joomla Templates, PHP

Clients: Private & Government Websites

WCAG, European Accessibility Act, Section 508, Equality Act, Legge Stanca

AWDD MEDIA

2010 (7 months) • Vancouver, Canada

Role: Frontend Developer

Drupal, PSD to HTML, CSS3, JavaScript, HTML5

Clients: Local Businesses

Self-employed

2008-2011 (3 years 5 months) • Italy

Role: Web Developer Joomla Websites

Clients: Local Businesses

Education

Ca' Foscari University, Venice

2004 - 2008 (3 years 6 months)

Degree, Information Technology

Grade: 107/110

ITIS Max Plank

1999 - 2004 (5 years)

High school diploma, Information Technology

Grade: 100/100